## MD RAKIB HASAN

Address: Building no.-24/F Azimpour Govt. Colony (South) Post TSO- Lalbagh, Dhaka 1205

Primary Mobile No: **01916909760**Secondary Mobile No: **01886909760**Emergency Contact No: 01672950494

Primary Email: rakibscm4@gmail.com
Alternate Email: rakib.hasan@foodpanda.com.bd

LinkedIn Id: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-rakib-hasan-2b437aa8/



#### **Career Objective:**

Highly focused with a comprehensive understanding of logistics, procurement, and the supply chain. generating ideas & inputs to contribute to the growth of the company demonstrating creativity and leadership.

### **Career Summary:**

A Supply Chain Professional with invaluable knowledge of managing projects, resources, and staff in an effective and efficient manner. I have been working in the field of procurement since 2016 increasing efficiency through spending Analysis, improving supplier base with improved delivery quality through supplier evaluation, overall, I am enjoying this work.

### **Special Qualification:**

Experienced to handle all type of Procurement Operation, Inbound & Outbound Logistics management, and solving issues. Supply Chain Strategy/SOP creation, review, Expert in using excel for Analytics, Forecast, optimization.

#### **Employment History:**

Total Year of Experience: 12.7 yrs.

1. Senior Executive, SCM (Vendor management) (1.5 yrs.)

(October, 2020 - Continuing)

#### Foodpand Bangladesh a concern of Delivery Hero-Germany

Foodpanda Bangladesh limited. Navana Pristine Pavilion Level 8 Gulshan 2, Dhaka-1212

### Area of Expertise

Distribution/ Supply Chain Management (0.4 yrs.), Inventory management (0.4 yrs.), Retail Management (0.4 yrs.)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

Monitor daily inventory status, develop market intelligence and commercial Information system to ensure the right price and better forecasting. Reduce supply shortage by 90% by developing monitoring modules and alternative sources of supply. Hand inexperience on import procedure. Communication with overseas suppliers, implementing an annual activity calendar that helped to manage appropriate quantity purchase at the right price at the right time that has a serious seasonal impact.

#### 2. Sr. Executive, SCM (Procurement and logistics Management) (4.5 yrs.)

(April, 2016 - October, 2020)

#### Unimart Limited a concern of United Group.

United House: 23-26 road: 90-91 Gulshan-2, Dhaka

#### Area of Expertise

Distribution/ Supply Chain Management (1.5 yrs.), Purchase/ Procurement (1.5 yrs.), Supply Chain (1.5 yrs.)

## **Duties/Responsibilities**

Ensure purchasing according to company guidelines and procedure. Supporting the direct & indirect supervisors in achieving the organizational goals. demand analysis on the market level to co-ordinate maximum satisfaction of the stakeholders by providing the

right products to the right customers at the right time at the right place in the right condition in the right quantity at the right cost. Crafting procurement annual planning. Taking prompt actions for emergency purchases in emergency cases and big purchases for special occasions. Maintaining a close relationship with concerned programs, enterprises, accounts department, and other internal & external stakeholders in order to ensure smooth operation at the lowest possible cost. Conducting regular sourcing for better supply market exploration. Any other task assigned by the management.

#### 3. Sr. Officer procurement and BTL activation (2.4 yrs.)

(October, 2013 - March, 2016)

# Red Rocket a concern of Elite group

House: 14 road: 06 Gulshan-1, Dhaka

#### Area of Expertise

Advertising & Promotion (0.8 yrs.), Customer Relation (0.8 yrs.), Procurement (0.8 yrs.)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

The strategic sourcing, procurement planning, and supplier management plan to control appropriate goods and services at the company's desire cost level with highly efficient operations. Handover of project & ensure timeline/just-in-time sourcing of required material or service. Approve project budget based on precedence and or present market survey. Procurement as per approved budget. Develop alternative suppliers for qualitative & quantitative improvement in procurement. Maintain separate files (soft & hard) for every project currently in hand & submit monthly reports stating procurement status & next month's budget. Connecting with marketing and PR colleagues to promote the event. Manage advertising campaigns (ATL, BTL, and Outdoor), sponsorship, event, and activation. Postevent evaluation (including data entry and analysis and producing reports. Any other task assigned by the management

#### 4. Officer, Events and Brand communication (3.9 yrs.)

(January, 2009 - December, 2012)

### **Papyrus Communication Limited.**

Road # 5 house # 154 Niketon, Gulshan, Dhaka.

#### Area of Expertise

Advertising & Promotion (3.9 yrs.)

#### **Duties/Responsibilities**

Liaising with clients and designers to create a brand for the event and organizing the production of tickets, posters, catalogs, and sales brochures, plus social media coverage. Coordinating & handling Exhibitor queries and troubleshooting on the day of the event to ensure that all runs smoothly. Receiving & delivering letters, drafting, replies the customer/guests & other queries, post-event evaluation (including data entry and analysis, and producing reports.

### **Academic Qualification:**

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pass. Year	Duration
Master of Business Studies (MBS)	Accounting	National University (Titumir College Dhaka)	First Class,	2010	one year
Bachelor of Business Studies (BBS)	Accounting	National University (Titumir College Dhaka) Second Class		2009	four years
HSC	Business Studies	Sreepur Degree College. Jessore Bord	CGPA:3.2	2005	two years
SSC	Huminites	Sreepur MC pilot High School, Jessore Bord	CGPA:2.38	2003	-

#### **Training Summary:**

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Procurement Management	Procurement evaluation, Strategy procurement, Modern SCM strategy, Better Negotiation strategy, Cost Saving	Dhaka Chamber of Commerce (DCCI)	Bangladesh	Motijheel Dhaka Bangladesh	2019	2 Days

Shipping Procedures for Export, Import & Customs Formalities	Import procedures (PI, L/C, Commercial Invoice), Banking procedures for import, Custom Procedures for import and Export, Transport procedures on Shipping, Air and Track and many more	Dhaka Chamber of Commerce (DCCI)	Bangladesh	Motijheel , Dhaka Bangladesh	2019	2 days
Business Analytics using Excel	MS Excel, Conditional Formatting, Pivot Table, Count if-Sum	Training Bangla	Bangladesh	Pallabi , Mirpur Dhaka Bangladesh	2019	19hour
Unleash Your True Potential	Four Cloud, Zohar Window, Strategical managing people,	Don Samdany Facititation and Consultancy	Bangladesh	Gulshan CGP 2 Dhaka 1212	2018	3days
Human Resource Management	To achieved company goal strategic planning, motivation to workers, salary, compliance and necessary function Human resource management.	Bangladesh small & cottage industries corporation (basic)	Bangladesh	Uttara model Town , Uttara, Dhaka.	2013	26th - 30th May 13
Office management	Windows 07, XP operating system. Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Internet Browsing etc.	Bejoy Computer Tanning Institute (BCTI)	Bangladesh	102 .Green Road. Dhaka -1215. Bangladesh.	2010	6 month

# **Career and Application Information:**

Looking For : Mid-Level Job
Available For : Full Time
Present Salary : Tk. 65000
Expected Salary : Tk. 95000

Preferred Job Category : Commercial/Supply Chain

Preferred District : Cox's Bazar, Dhaka Preferred Country : Canada, Qatar

Preferred Organization Types : Manufacturing (FMCG), Multinational Companies, Travel Agent

# **Specialization:**

Fields of Specialization	Description
<ul> <li>Retail Management</li> <li>Demand Planning</li> <li>E commerce Business</li> </ul>	Experienced to handle all types of Procurement operations, Inbound & Outbound Logistics management, and Case solving. Business Process Blueprinting (BPB) for configuring ERP. Supply Chain Strategy/SOP creation, review, and implementation align with Corporate Strategy. Sourcing and Inventory Management.  Expert in using excel for Analytics, Forecast, optimization.

# **Extra-Curricular Activities:**

Good at interpersonal skills. Able to coordinate and work effectively in groups. Possess effective presentation (multimedia, slide, and oral) skills. Able to work in a strong and demanding environment. Highly flexible and adaptable performer adaptable at multi-tasking and thriving in a fast-paced environment while coordinating numerous time-sensitive projects. Innovative and creative. Ability to manage team-based work. Highly ambitious with the growth plan. Sound functional knowledge to solve job-related problems. Deadline oriented.

## **Language Proficiency:**

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	High	Medium	Medium

# **Personal Details:**

Father's Name : Md Nazrul Islam Mother's Name : Hera nur Nahar Date of Birth : August 11, 1986

Gender : Male

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Bangladeshi

National Id No. : 7327846148

Religion : Islam
Passport No : EA0349053
Passport Issue Date : 4/9/2019

Permanent Address : Horindi, Shripur, Sreepur, Magura 7610

Current Location : Dhaka Blood Group : A+

## Reference (s):

Reference: 01

Name : MD. Golam Morshed

Organization : Square Food and Beverage Limited

Designation : Senior Manager Commercial Address : Mohakhali C/A Gulshan Dhaka

Phone (Off.) :

Mobile : 01713-090359

E-Mail : morshed@squaregroup.com

Relation : Professional

Reference: 02

MD. Liton Akando

Trust Infinity Firms Limited Chief Executive Officer Zoo Road Mirpur 2 Dhaka

01794 800000 01713 303765

akandaliton@gmail.com

Professional